Personal Accidental Insurance: Personal
accidental insurance is
different from your health insurance. Many times
you people ask the question that
what is personal accident in health insurance policy? If it is
not there then accident in
hospitalisation is covered in your health and bravery
policy. If
any hospitalization occurs due to an accident then it is covered. Personal
accident policy is your fixed benefit
policy, meaning if there is accidental death or
disability which is permanent or
temporary in nature then a
percentage is paid to you accordingly. So it depends on
what that disability is and
accordingly you are paid a percentage.
So as an example, if there is an
accident due to which you have to be hospitalized then that will be covered by
your health insurance
policy. Suppose there is some
temporary disability due to that, but you got injured or underwent
surgery and the doctor said that you will have to take
bed rest, then how will that be covered in that? The
insurance company gives you a benefit for the number of weeks you are at home for the loss of income.  This is part of
personal accidental insurance, so we will
understand in detail later. Today we are going to talk about
Bajaj Allianz Personal Garden plan. There are a
lot of requests to cover gas products,
so we are covering this plan. In this plan, we will
talk about what
is covered, how long, what is the eligibility
criteria and what benefits you get in this
policy. At the end, we will talk about the
premium. Before starting the video, I would
like to introduce myself. My name is Goodlink. I am a
Certified Financial Planner. Every week I
bring videos for you so that your
personal financial life becomes your happy life
because the tagline of our company is also
creating a wealth of happiness. Let's move
towards the video which is today about Alliance Personal
Garden plan. So, as I
told you, this is personal accidental insurance, in
which accident disability, whether it is
permanent or temporary, is basically termed as
PPT and PD, PDS,
Permanent Partial Disability and PAT,
Permanent Total Disability. If any of these happens, then
you will get this  Accidental
insurance pays, so first we will talk about
which plans are available
inside Bajaj Allianz Personal Garden. All types
of plans are available in all, short
is available from 10 lakh to 25 lakh, 10 lakh
comes in Plan A, 15 lakh comes in Plan B,
20 lakh comes in Plan C and 25 lakh
comes in Plan D. We will see its benefits further.
Entry agent policy at 18 years, an
adult and 65 years maximum, minimum
18 years, maximum 65 years, children can enter
this policy after 5 years and further
an dependent can stay in the policy
till 21 years, you can take this policy as an individual
and can also take a family floater,
so these policies are available whose
risk level is one, so here the
risk level is defined in personal accidental,
your type is determined,
your
risk level is defined according to your occupation, so here
only the list  This policy is given to risk level one
and we will
talk about who all are covered under it and when it comes to creative jobs
whose area is accountancy and
doctors and lawyers architects teachers and
similar occupations whose administrative area is
less and these are the basic jobs, they are covered under
this policy so in case of death
if there is accidental death then you get
100% of summation in case of permanent total
disability you get 200% of summation in case of
permanent partial disability
you get different
percentages defined and that is the table, I am
sharing that table in front of you, if there is a general
disability then maximum up to 70% is given,
70% of summation is given for the amount you have
taken the policy, if you have become disabled then
20% will be single disability, it is defined how much,
5% 10% if there will be injury in a unit
then 50% so this is the way you are seeing it.  It is
defined from 5% to 70%. Depending on which
injury you have suffered and which part of your body has become disabled,
this percentage is given to you. It will be decided on the
table only. So
if you are taking such a family photo policy, then
100% coverage is given to the policy holder. The late
husband has taken the policy, he will get 100% coverage.
Mainly, if he is in the first category,
if we talk about 70% sharing, then the
entire 70% will be given to the spouse and children.
The percentage of spouse and children is defined, so
if there was 70% sharing, then they will get 50% because the spouse
gets 50% and the children get 25%, then
50% of 70%, out of which 35%, so all the benefits will be
halved for the spouse in the same manner.
For children, it will be reduced to 1/4. 24%
transportation of human remains,
from the place of death to the cremation ground, so the
cost of transportation is given to the family. Rs.
5000 please and you  Percentage lower
children education bonus is given to your kids in
case of death and permanent
total disabilities ₹5000 per child and if the age
of the child is less than 19 years then one
time only is correct, basically this accidental
hospitalization, accidental hospital
is also tax in your plan, along with this there is also
hospital confinement allowance,
if all this happens in an accident then according to the
plan you are given a maximum benefit of ₹2500 till your birthday
but maximum 30
days, we will see according to the plan
how much will be paid in which, cumulative bonus is
also available, in this plan 10% off time is
given, in case of no claim maximum it will go up
to 50% and if a claim is taken then it will be
deducted in this proportion,
you can renew this plan from time to time, as
I told you the maximum
entry in this is 65 years but you can renew it for
lifetime but after 66 years
you  There will be a restriction that you have to
choose the plane which you have a problem with and if you
want to change this plan at the time of renewal, then you can do that. You get that option. If you want to change
this plan, then this is Plan A, Plan B, Plan
C, Plan D, that option is available only for renewal. Initially, we had talked about the
coverage of these plans. The
plane image of Shamis Shot is
10 lux maximum in Plan B, 15
lux in Plan C, 20 lux in Plan A and 25 lux in Plan A. So, the
baseline features are
basically the features. I am
dividing the disability into three different parts.
First is accidental death, second is
permanent total disability, third is
permanent partial disability, fourth is
temporary total disability, which is
called weekly benefit. So, if you have a
semi-annual plan of 10 lux, then the
death benefit will be given 100%.
Permanent Total  Disability Benefit Plan B is
100% which is 20 lakhs here and PPT like the
table we talked about, permanent
partial disability will be done at the percentage according to the table,
temporary total
disability which is 100 lakhs per 5000 weeks, so it will be done at
100 lakhs per 5000 weeks in case
of temporary disability, similarly if
your policy is of 15 lakhs then there you
get 100% death benefit, 200% permanent
total disability body and permanent
partial disability temporary
total disability is ₹5000 maximum 100
lakhs third plan is Plan C where there is
coverage of 20 lakhs and your death benefit is 100%,
200% is your permanent total
disability benefit, permanent partial
disability benefit is on the table and
temporary total disability benefit  7500 per
week but we will talk about 100 lakhs in plain text. 25 lakhs
is the time-bound sum assured. 100% will be
paid to you in case of death. 200% in case
of permanent total disability or permanent
partial disability will be paid on the
table which
is the benefit of temporary total disability. Date is 10000 per
week, maximum 100 lakhs in this you
can take allowances. See the additional premium.
Two things are accidental hospitalization
and hospital confinement allowance. If you
want to add these two things then you have to pay a small
additional premium. So I don't think
with a policy of 10 lakhs you are
given accidental hospitalization benefit.
With a policy of ₹2 lakhs, ₹3 lakhs with a policy of ₹20 lakhs, ₹
4 lakhs with a policy of 20 lakhs and ₹25 lakhs,
you are given coverage
for accidental hospitalization along with this there is
hospital confinement allowance which we
talked about.  It was up to 2500, so the limit
is specified here, but in plan A it is
Rs 1000, in plan B it is Rs 1500, plan Iman
2000 and plan Iman 2500 and this is the limit but 30
days maximum is given to you, so now I will
talk about the premium scheme, so the premium
I have taken for plan D in which the highest
plan is ₹25 lakh and here
I have considered a family of three and here I
would like to tell you that the premium for personal accident is
relief from throat
till 65 years, so here I have taken 438 for three people
and if there is a child of 10 years then the tax for them is
25 lakh, so you remember what I
told you, 50% goes to the spouse and 25% to the
dependent child, so 50% coverage will be
of the spouse and 25% to the dependent
child, so the premium that will come, the
premium has been calculated here, so by
adding the premium of all three, the premium of the husband and the wife and  The
premium of all three children is being calculated by adding
six, three, double, then with 18%
GST it will become 75374.
This is the base premium in which I have
not added advance, mother, you
add advance in it, from which points two advances
were accident, hospital,
confinement, alloys, if you add them
for all three then your premium becomes 848. If you
add 18% GST in it then the premium
becomes ₹10000. So you are seeing that
in ₹10000 you are being given all these benefits
which we have just talked about above, so this was
from my side, Bajaj Allianz's personal
garden plane, if you want to add on anything,
I missed something in this plane or there is
some additional feature, if you want to share your experience,
you can do that, it will be
helpful for other people also and if you
want to join my channel, our WhatsApp number,
email ID is mentioned below, you can reach out.
Quick reminder before you go, if
you have not subscribed to our channel yet, do
subscribe and get the right
information and  The right time and thank you so much
watching the video on the match take care see you
next week with a new video thank you